[Music]
hello and thank you for watching what's
new in the service Management Area
service management you can ask it's a
very are important area in uh in the
business Central customers it was very
popular on premises is is getting its
direction in SAS and especially for
manufacturing companies who are
producing stuff they would like to
control and monitor and repair the items
but there are also multiple companies
independent service
providers you might also ask why service
management when we uh or investment into
this area together with field service
integration which is also presented in
this uh in this release it might be a
little bit confusing but it's not
because business Central always give you
choice you can do like the same things
or achieve the same result in a very
very different manners which better fits
to specific company needs and if some
companies has a need for features
available under field service
product it's a it's great you can use it
but also for number of scenarios
integrated uh service management model
is more than enough and we continue our
investment into this area we started in
the previous release where we added demo
data and setup data so you can now
easily demonstrate functionality out of
the box but in this release we decided
to align uh service management
experience with other areas such as a
sales or project areas and my name is
Andre PCO and I will be doing demos for
you I will demonstrate this
functionality But first you can also uh
watch the demo and the setup uh video
from the previous Business Center launch
event you can find it it on our YouTube
channel together with other interesting
videos and the current video will be
also there available later all right
it's a 10 minutes and you know what to
do uh and how to demonstrate service
management now back to the product this
is service Management rooll Center and
it is configured it has demo data
everywhere except some places let's take
a look for example at service quote
service quote doesn't have number series
defined but but now you have a nice
window which actually notifies you that
something is missing and help you to
select and set up
service service area let's go to the
quote and we decide to use the same
number seres as available for sales
quote okay that's a good one good
start okay service quote created uh
number series you can see you don't see
this demonstration will be mainly about
what you don't see actually you don't
see the number field here in the header
because number series is configured to
be automatic so like it doesn't allow
user to modify it doesn't allow user to
select a different one it just assigns
the number so it makes sense to see it
right here and not take place under as
areas all right what next let's select
some customer
pick our favorite one and what you
notice you can see attachment area and
document attachment was initialized with
a quantity one if you go to the list you
can see that there is a some document
based on its name as I call it it's
copied from the customer card so okay so
from customer to service we can get
something let's uh scroll down and uh
now we can we can select service
item okay I see one service item and I
see interesting description don't use in
contract so it's actually giving us some
hint again this presentation not about
what not only what you see what you
don't see let's go to the list of item
uh service
items service items and you can see
there are two one is called don't use in
contracts and another blocked completely
hm interesting let's open it because we
have a new tole uh field here which is
called blocked which allows you to
decide how do you want to block specific
service item because for some reason you
don't want to have long-term contract
for maintenance contract for specific
items but it's okay to do ad hoc
repairments that's fine that's fair or
you want to completely stop maintenance
for for this one then you can block it
fully all right so I have service item
uh which I cannot use in contracts and I
have another one which is blocked
completely okay let's create another
service item as we are here anyway and
we select the
item as 100 and again I see only one but
let me go to the list of
items let's go to list of the
items and do the same search as
100 and I have two items here which is
starts with S1 100 but you do not see
the second one why because it is again
blocked let's open let's open the
card scroll down scroll down scroll down
and in the price and sales and service
you can see the service toggle available
which is actually blocking item also
also you can see the similar toggles
available per variant level so you can
actually block individual variants from
service and sales and purchase as it was
added before but it is now all aligned
all right service blocked as we are here
let's also take a look at the item which
we can see and you can see that this
item has also attachment troubleshooting
guide and we can instruct where this
data should go it should go to the
service Transaction what does it mean
let's uh let's go back to our service
item and select this
item yes I want to copy skill code and
and service details and also attachment
attachment got initialized now it is
copied from the item to service item all
right let's select some
customer and return back to the to the
to the list of uh service items selected
finally we back to the list of the
service item uh selected for Sal service
quote all right this is the new one
which we just added let's use it all
right I selected it what else can I do
here because probably it's not all the
changes let's go to
the service item
work and if I will scroll down you can
see the select items action familiar to
you by by sales and purchase documents
and now also added to project planning
lines you can do it uh bulk selection
here as well in the service good I
selected three lines all of them are
inserted also item references are
available in the in the service area as
well let's pick some
barcode which we can scan of course if
we if using a warehouse handheld
device there is a separate session about
it as well all right so it was populated
good uh what else we can do we can print
and we can print as attachment as well
so now we have lines all good now we
have attachment added even more so
service quote added as an attachment as
well now let's try to uh convert service
quote to service
order right I have now service order
available uh with two
attachments probably it's interesting to
add one more okay now we have a even
more
attachments service order as well so
works here all good let's scroll down to
the to the list of items and now we open
a different view so instead of service
uh service item worksheet we will open
service lines
right uh it also support select items it
also supports uh item references and
also I wanted to show you it has
attachment details hm attachment we can
see two troubleshooting guide which is
flow from service item remember it was
configured for per service item level
but installation guide this one is
configured for for this specific item so
you can see that attachments are moving
to from Master data to the documents and
the posted transactions as well all
right about posting let's try to do post
post
experienc that people already notice
that something looks
different you don't see something okay
what we don't see let's go to the
service order itself and try to do
posting there as
well you don't see invoicing options so
you can see only shipment and shipment
consumption why so because of the user
setup user setup
where we added service invoice posting
policy uh similar to purchase and sales
areas where you can decide on how you
want to process uh orders like and
invoices separately from a shipment or
together or maybe it is per user all
right now I'm switching to
mandatory and if I will try to post now
then I don't have much options now I I
just can press yes and the shipment and
in voice will be processed not
consumption all right now we're talking
about service
invoices uh maybe a couple of notes
worth uh mentioning so first of all we
added service invoice and credit memo
here so now that's uh that's available
you can
uh you can benefit from
the from the select item and attachments
here as well but uh I wanted to show a
different aspect of service management
service contracts let's create a new
service
contract okay I will use a template
predefined in the demo
data and I will select customer as
well mm attachment again you know it we
can do select service items again you
can add multiple ones at once of course
we have only one because two others are
blocked one blocked completely and the
second one is blocked for service
contract so we need to deal with what is
available all right we will pick one you
can see attachments here as well now
let's put some
value and sign the contract all right we
signing the contract and uh because of
the dates system tries to create invoice
for the remaining of the month yes we
will do that okay invoice
created it is here and and I also change
my uh work date let's slightly move to
to the next
months okay next month and try to create
service invoice for the next quarter
right okay now I have two uh two
invoices you can see that next invoice
date is updated and the next invoice
period is here uh what
if I'm not happy with this service
invoices for example
I I maybe I don't like amount or maybe I
don't like the fact that it's two of
them I I cannot change them it's a it's
a limitation uh we have a restrictions
because it's linked to Service uh
service Ledger entries all right let's
uh reset my change can I delete
it actually you can but but but there
are some limitations you can only delete
starting from the end because we already
have invoice for this Delta and for the
whole quarter we need to delete in the
right in the right order starting from
the end okay let's close this
one find another invoice with the all
amount amount for the quarter and delete
it yeah dates will be restored that's
good now we can also delete the first
one all right
these dates also should be restored
except this specific uh invoice is for
prepayment that's why uh it's not here
all right so number is zero now I can
create a new service invoices how
many it will create a one one combined
so now I will actually send one invoice
to my to my customer for the whole uh
details so this uh this gives you some
capability on to review documents and
redo if something needs to be redone
that is like one of the most voted
product suggestions so we implemented it
uh for you to give you uh better
experience so what we saw we saw that
service management is now operates very
closely to uh other areas like sales or
projects you can use a blocking document
attachment bulk processing like
selections or item reference
you can Define invoicing policy and you
can also deal with service invoices
linked to the contract which has some
limitations in the past not anymore what
I want to say say is of course thank you
thank you for watching but also for uh
contribution for registering ideas for
voting for participating in the
conversation via VIA engage and sharing
valuable insights and also for testing
in the early preview thank you very much
also makes sense to explore other
sessions related so if you interested in
the field service
integration watch this session also be
aware that field service integration
integrates two jobs that's very
interesting or project so take a look at
the project area as well if you decided
to use service project inside business
Central take a look at the new time shet
experience or improved time shet
experience and uh this is a list of also
valuable resources where you can find
the Microsoft representatives and uh all
information available uh for you thank
you
again